We're builders. We think in systems,
processes, repeatable workflows. And now
that we can delegate to agents, whether
that's on Claude code or open claw,
whatever you're using, we can apply that
same systems mindset to marketing our
business without needing to become
world-class marketers ourselves. You
know, marketing is one of those things
that as builders we know we should be
doing more of it, but it pulls us away
from the work we actually want to be
doing. The thing is, most marketing work
follows a pattern, and once you see
these patterns, you can turn these
processes into skills and hand them to
agents. Today, I'll show you four of the
skills that I built to run the marketing
side of my business, and I'll walk
through how I structured each one, and
how I delegate them to my agents using
open claw and Claude. And honestly, this
approach applies way beyond marketing.
Every role in your organization should
be looking for these repeatable
processes that can be turned into
skills. If we haven't met yet, I'm Brian
Castle, and I help builders and teams
stay ahead of the curve when it comes to
building with AI. And I also send a free
weekly newsletter called the Builder
Briefing. That's a free 5-minute read to
keep you sharp on what's actually
working. And today, I'll show you the
agent skill that I used to help me write
and send that newsletter. Anyway, you
can get yours by going to
buildermethods.com.
And if you're just getting into open
claw, I just launched a new course and
starter kit inside of Builder Methods
Pro where I walk through how I built my
team of agents, and it comes with a
ready to build spec so that you can
build your own custom dashboard for your
agents.
Now, as I walk through each of my
custom-built skills, I think what's most
important is for you to see how I think
about the strategy and the process
behind these because that's really what
matters when it comes to skills and
processes in your business. You can
literally just describe what you want to
do and what your business goals are,
explain those to Claude or ChatGPT or
Gemini, and have it help you build out a
custom-built skill that fits your
specific needs for your processes. So,
I'm going to walk through mine. Here's
the first one. I call this my radar scan
process. And so, basically every morning
in Telegram, so I have these, you know,
these four different agents. These are
all operating on open claw on my Mac
mini on my desk. One of my agents is I
named this agent Veil, and this is like
my marketing agent. And so, Veil is
responsible for running the radar scan,
which the agent does every morning, and
I received this one today. It runs
actually at 4:00 in the morning, so it's
here when I wake up, and I I don't wake
up at 4:00 a.m. by the way.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh but it's there waiting for when I
wake up. And so, here's is today's radar
scan, and there's a link, and this is
actually pointing to a markdown file
that lives on my file system and also in
Dropbox. And I'm opening it up in a
custom-built app that I created called
Brain Down, and that is my markdown
reader, markdown writer, and it really
makes it easy for my agents and I to be
able to pass these markdown files around
to each other. But this is actually a
markdown file that my agent wrote up,
and it basically summarizes a bunch of
mostly tweets that are happening in my
industry that came through sometime in
the past 24 hours. These are people and
companies and like industry news and
influencers and thinkers that I really
like to follow and I like to keep tabs
on. And so, my agent my agent kind of
collects those and analyzes a lot of
like incoming feeds, and then decides
which ones the agent thinks, based on my
training, are most relevant for me and
my business and could potentially become
material that I might use or comment on
or, you know, react to in various
content. I actually haven't walked
through today's report just yet, but I
will later today. So, how is this
actually happening? Let's Let's see how
I set it up. So, it starts with a skill
in my custom collection of skills. I
call this one content radar scan, and
inside that folder, I've got the main
skill file, that's this, and then I've
got a couple of references. So, the
skill file itself, I've got some
configuration stuff. I'll talk a bit
more about this other tool called Spark
Drop, that's another custom-built tool
that I that I'm using. I'm actually in
the middle of building this right now,
and I might share this on the channel
sometime later. Anyway, there's a lot
more to it than this, but this is where
my agents can pull my training for my
interests from. Now, you don't have to
have a custom-built tool for that. What
I did for a while before I started
building this Spark Drop app is I had
this like training material in markdown
files, you know, stored inside the skill
itself. So, I would have a file on like
my voice and the tone. I would have a
file on the topics and interests that I
wanted to focus on and that sort of
thing. And I trained that from Claude
from helping me write lots of stuff over
over a couple of years now. So, that's
where the training data comes from, and
then I give my agent this process, uh
starting with the radar sources. First,
fetch the training data from Spark Drop,
or you can read it from markdown files
if you have those. And then, scan all of
the radar sources for new activity since
the last run. And the last run happened
yesterday, so we're we're scanning for
the last 24 hours. So, the radar
sources, that's another important file
in here. So, this skill is referencing
this file right here called radar
sources. This is something that I'm
still in the process of building out.
It's a collection of XML RSS feeds, and
I grouped them into different feeds. One
is tracking the Anthropic team's tweets.
So, there's a lot of people on the
Claude team who are tweeting all the
time about about new releases, new
features. Same thing with the OpenAI
team, the team at Cursor, and then
another general list of like influencers
and people who I think are doing really
interesting work in building with AI
that I like to keep tabs on. I'm
naturally scrolling Twitter every day
just watching this stuff, but it's
really nice to have an agent who is
always watching and capturing this
stuff. So, I'm using an app that anyone
can use called rss.app.
And let's take a look at that. So, this
is a pretty cool tool. It works really
well. I think they have a free plan, but
I think I'm paying for it. Um so, if I
go into my feeds in my account, these
are the feeds of like X or Twitter. I
still call it Twitter, you know, X
feeds. So, for example, this is the one
that tracks Anthropic team's tweets, and
it's sort of just This is a feed of of
those tweets, but what the agent is
actually going to read is this XML feed,
and that looks like this. So, this is
much more It's not digestable for us,
but it's a lot more digestable for the
agent. And so, that's actually what I am
referencing here. I'm telling the agent
to go to that XML feed and read that for
each of these and to sort of like
analyze and scan through. And as you can
see, there's a there's a lot here that
that came through in the last, you know,
24 hours or so. So, the agent is
actually going to use its own judgment
and the training that I give it to
decide what's most relevant for me to
include in my daily report. And then,
the way that that is actually built in
this RSS feed is it's actually tracking
a Twitter search. So, if I look at that,
I go into Twitter or, you know, X, and
this is an actual search and then I'm
giving that search URL to the rss.app,
and that generates this XML feed, which
is then read by the agent. Okay, so
that's that piece. It's all just like
moving parts, one step at a time, one
big process, right? So, after the agent
reads those radar sources, filter for
relevance, some instruction on how to
choose what is interesting to me,
discard items that are, you know, have
these characteristics that I'm not
interested in, how to write the brief
entry, and what to write for each one,
and then output it to this file on my
actual file system, which is synced
using Dropbox, a little format for how
to name the file. Here's how I want the
file to be created in this type of
format with a bunch of examples built
into there, and then finally,
instructions to notify me via Telegram.
So, the agents are connected to my
Telegram, and I have that here. I like
to organize my Telegram into These are
my human friends, and these are my agent
friends.
So, then I get this message, and I also
instructed it, you know, don't give me
the whole report in the Telegram
message. I just want sort of an
overview, and then I can click into this
and open it up on my Brain Down app. And
that's how I handle all of my messages.
Like my other agent sends me daily
report, and these link to my AI to-do
list and yesterday's summary, and I can
see like the the Knicks score and the
Mets score. That's kind of cool. So,
this radar scan really helps me keep
tabs on what's happening in the in the
industry. It can help me come up with
new ideas for content, or I can use it
in my content development pipeline with
my agents to draw on ideas and help me
draft new stuff for YouTube or for
Twitter or for my newsletter.
All right, this next skill is one that I
used to create all of the branded
visuals throughout my business and my
brand. So, I did another whole deep dive
video on how I created this skill for
creating a brand visuals, but I'll show
you how I've been using it here again.
So, if you look at my website for
Builder Methods, you'll see these kind
of interesting illustrations throughout
the site. You know, there's all sorts of
different ones in here, but they all
follow a very consistent style, look and
feel. They always have a selection of
specific colors, and, you know, very
specific notes on how I want the
literally like the lines and the
illustrations and the shadows to be
built out so that on any page, anytime,
I can create So, no matter which page
I'm working on or if I'm creating like a
new workshop or a new session or an
image that I want to share on social
media, all of that can follow consistent
look and feel from, you know, I created
this months ago to the one that I'll
create tomorrow. All these images feel
connected. I think that's a really part
of branding and marketing in general.
So, how does this actually work? So,
here is a skill and and this is actually
inside of a special project that I call
a BM, you know, Builder Methods brand
illustrations. And so, there's one skill
in here and then inside that I've got
these mini projects for every individual
illustration that I create. So, for
example, yesterday I was preparing some
new like live sessions for members of
Builder Methods Pro and so, I wanted to
create an illustration that is used on
that. And so, for example, I that is on
our sessions list here and you and you
can see that that image is being used in
these thumbnails. So, this one went
through a few iterations, you know, and
and ultimately I was happy with this one
and you can see that the agent also
created some concepts like suggesting
like a few different descriptive
concepts of of what it might be and then
I I sort of greenlit one of these
concepts and then had it go ahead and
generate the image. So, it's generating
the illustration using the Google
ImageGen API. So, I'm using Claude and
Claude Code to prompt and to suggest the
concept for the illustration and then
I'm using the Google Gemini API to
actually generate the image because
Claude doesn't have an image generation
model built in. So, let's try it out,
shall we? Now, this is one that I
actually use like manually. It's not
happening automatically in the
background although I might start to
incorporate it into more of a content
pipeline at some point. But basically,
whenever I need an an illustration, I'll
just fire up this I just fire up this
project and then I have to work on it.
First, I start by running Claude and
then I'll do write brand illustrator and
then I'm going to give it a little bit
of a description of of what I want to do
here. So, I'll use voice dictation.
Create an illustration for a blog
article that's about marketing skills
for agents. I want to share a a set of
tools that my agents can use to help me
with marketing. All right, so that's the
overview of the description and then the
skill instructs my agent to go through
this creative like interviewing process
with me to first develop the concept for
what we want to do. So, first it's
asking me do I have like a visual
context like a screenshot of where this
image is going to be placed. I'll just
say no for now, that's fine. And then I
have a a set of brand colors that I
always wanted to use and I've built
these into the skill and you can see in
the references. So, I've got like colors
and idea mapping and and like a visual
world for like the types of objects that
might be found in my brand. I went
deeper into all this stuff in my other
video on how I created this skill, but I
just want to show you how it's all wired
up here. So, yeah, let's go with the
let's go with coral. All right, so what
size of of illustration and and
configuration? Let's go with a scene and
I'll use the typical dimensions for
that. All right, so before it gets to
work on the actual illustration, Claude
is going to use my training and my
references and the information that I've
provided to generate three potential
con- concepts and it's going to describe
those in detail and that's really
important. Before we get into creating
an image, I want a very descriptive
concept that we can use as the prompt
that we will then send over to Google.
All right, so it gives me an option
option A, option B, option C. Yeah, I
kind of like this option A, the agent's
toolbox. So, let's go with that and it's
using the ask user questions system to
make it easy to to sort of collaborate
with the agent on this. I'm going to
just select that. Okay, so now what it's
going to do is inside of my projects
folder, you can see it has already
created this new folder. It dated it
today and it's also creating a little
project.md file which is documenting
everything that we've discussed so far.
So, it has the the prompt that it's
going to be sending to Google. It has
the options that it presented. It has
the one that I selected and now it's
actually going to send the request to
the Google ImageGen API to start
generating the first take at this
illustration. Okay, so V1, the first
take at this illustration is done. Let's
take a look and yeah, there is a
marketing toolbox with a bunch of
marketing things inside. So, you know,
from here I would typically go through a
couple more iterations to maybe dial it
in and and give it some feedback and and
then select a winner like an an actual
user usable one. But this is actually a
pretty good first stab at it. And as you
can see, it already has the built-in
style and level of detail that I like to
have in all of my illustrations. It
already feels pretty consistent. And so,
that's how I generate visuals for all of
the public-facing marketing stuff that I
do.
Now, this next skill is made possible by
today's sponsor, Waymark Video. So, if
you're a builder who's also producing
video content, whether that's tutorials,
demos, or just building in public, you
know the bottleneck isn't recording.
It's everything that comes after,
turning your long-form videos into short
clips for YouTube Shorts or LinkedIn or
TikTok. That's a whole job in itself.
Waymark Video handles that. You can give
it a long-form video recording or a
YouTube link and its AI identifies the
most engaging moments and then cuts them
into share-ready clips. It can even
reframe them into vertical format and
add animated captions. And all these
little tasks, that stuff really adds up.
So, automating that is huge. Now, as a
builder, what makes Waymark Video
interesting to me is their API. So, all
of those capabilities, the clipping,
transcription, summarization, searching
for moments, that's all available
through a simple REST API with a
pay-as-you-go pricing model, which means
I can plug it into my agent workflows
just like any other tool. And they've
also published an agent skill on
ClaudeHub and that handles the full
workflow from uploading a video to
submitting a clipping job, pulling for
results, and then delivering the
finished clips. So, if you're using
OpenClaude, you can immediately plug it
in with your agent or you can just
download the skill zip and then use it
with Claude or any other agent. You
know, that's where I could see this
fitting into my setup. You know, I
publish these long-form videos on
YouTube and then my agent can pick it up
and run it through Waymark Video's API
and generate a batch of short clips and
then have them ready for me to review
and push out to my other platforms. And
so, for someone who likes to build in
public, that kind of automated
repurposing pipeline, that's exactly
what I want. So, you can try Waymark
Video for free by going to waymark.ai or
if you want to build it into your agent
workflows, their API is pay-as-you-go.
So, you can just grab your API key and
go or use their skill and plug it right
in with your agent.
All right, so the last skill that I want
to talk about or the last set of skills
that I want to talk about is the one
that helps me write and send my weekly
newsletter. You may have heard me talk
about this on the channel. It's
available at buildermethods.com. I call
my newsletter the Builder Briefing and
folks join that here. But here's what an
issue of my Builder Briefing newsletter
actually looks like. It's a pretty
simple text-based email and you know,
it's got a simple subject line. I number
each issue. I've got the date. You know,
this is the one that I sent last week.
It always starts with a sort of like a
mini article on you know, something that
I've been thinking about and a mental
model or an observation that I want to
share with my fellow builders. And then
below that, you know, I've got a couple
of other sections where I'll talk about
my recent YouTube video and another
section where I talk about what I'm
currently building. And sometimes I add
in a few additional sections into this.
So, very minimal formatting, some you
know, I've got my sign-off, some lines,
and and some some styling built into it.
But it used to be that I would create
this manually in ConvertKit or it's
called kit.com now and you know, a lot
of like tedious formatting and clicking
of buttons and making sure that it gets
scheduled and making sure that it looks
right and and all that kind of stuff.
And then of course, writing the content.
So, and you know, thanks to these skills
that I use with Claude, I don't actually
have to do any of the setup work inside
of my email marketing tool whatsoever.
So, now every week when I'm creating my
Builder Briefing newsletter, I come into
Claude and I have a project called BM
Newsletter for Builder Methods
newsletter. Here is a folder with some
of the more recent ones and then in this
project, I have a Claude Skills folder
and it has two skills actually that I'll
show you. First, I'm going to look at
the newsletter writer skill and this is
the skill that actually helps me craft
my message and the content that's going
to go into each one of these sections.
So, let me show you how this usually
plays out. So, I'm going to open up
Claude and the first thing that I'll do
is I'll pull up that newsletter writer
skill by using the slash command. Now,
normally I get my message out using a
long voice message. I I usually go out
and and take a walk for 20 minutes and
talk through the idea or observation or
insight that I want to share in this
week's newsletter. Just a a brain dump
of what I want to talk about. Today for
this demo, I'm just going to do a much
more abbreviated version of that. So,
I'll use voice dictation here. The main
message for this newsletter should be
about how I go about creating skills for
my agents to carry out my marketing
processes. So, again, normally I would
go into much more detail in terms of
like sharing what I want to say, but
that's not actually how it ends up
getting presented or or written out. The
agent is going to do that, but it we're
going to go through a process here
starting with the main message, but then
we're going to go section by section and
Claude, using my newsletter writer
skill, is going to get all of the
essential information out of me in order
to be able to assemble my newsletter.
So, first it's it's actually going back
and checking recent examples so that it
that helps with like training its voice
and style. And so, now it actually gave
me a draft for what that main message
section could be. You know, this is what
will go in this top section of the
newsletter. So, you know, again,
normally I would read this through and I
typically go through a round of maybe
three to five revisions. I would give
some creative feedback. I really start
to dial in the message and get a a much
better draft. And then even later, after
we send it into Kit before I send it
out, I'll do a little bit of hand
editing as well. For the sake of this
demo to keep it moving, I'm just going
to go ahead and approve this. Good to
go. Okay, so now the agent is going to
move on to the subject line and the
pre-header. And so this is the next step
that I have instructed it to do. So it
actually suggested a couple of pretty
good subject lines and some pre-headers.
And actually I'm going to go with
something a little bit different for the
subject line. Subject: Marketing skills.
Pre-header: One. I'll use its first
suggestion there. Okay, so now we're
moving on into the next section, which
is the YouTube section. And that's
typically like this. And and sometimes I
don't have a recent video that I want to
share, so it's asking me like are we
going to include a YouTube video for
this week or not? And by the way, let's
just take a look at the skill itself so
you can see how how this is happening.
The skill is instructing the agent to
read through my recent finished
newsletter examples. I like to look at
the recent ones because my style might
change from week to week. And then a
little bit more info about like patterns
and how to speak like me and and my
voice. And then we get into the
workflow, you know, the drafting of the
main message which we just saw. Then we
get the subject line and pre-header
worked out and then we get into this
YouTube video section. So I'm literally
instructing the agent on how to go
step-by-step to get what we need for
each section. And I'll say yes, let's
let's use this most recent video and I'm
just going to grab that URL so that it
can set up the link for me. So that's
the URL and I'm going to use the same
description that I put at the top of the
video and I'm going to drop that in here
and then the agent is going to write new
version of that to go in the on YouTube
section. Okay, so as you can see here,
it actually formatted it the way that it
will ultimately look in my email
newsletter. So that's that's looking
good. Yes, we're going to promote a
podcast episode this week. So I co-host
a podcast called the panel and we did
release an episode last week and that
one was called can AI be a CRM? So I do
want to mention that in next week's
newsletter. Now we didn't have much of a
description on that one, but I'm just
going to paste it in. Okay, so that's
looking good. And then are we going to
have a behind the build section this
week? Yes, we're going to have a behind
the build section this week and I'm
going to talk more about how I'm coming
along with my SparkDrop app for managing
my content development pipeline in
collaboration with my agents. And again,
in a normal situation, I would be going
back and forth and provide a lot more
input on each one of these, but I just
want to go through the process for the
sake of this demo. That's good. So this
is a much easier back and forth than for
me to go, you know, into into Kit and
like and click all the buttons and
format each thing and and make sure that
it looks just right. I just like to be
able to, you know, give my input and
approve and know that it's going to get
assembled the way that I always want it.
So so far, using that newsletter writing
skill, it created this full markdown
version of this newsletter. So this is a
good start. And so now we have the
content worked out and we have the
headlines and the and we have the
subject line, the pre-header, we've got
the headlines, the links are all worked
out. So the most important part like
creating the content, that was done
using the newsletter writer skill. But
next comes actually assembling it into
an HTML email and sending it out.
And so for that, I have one more skill.
This is sort of a bonus skill that I'm
going to show you here. And that one is
called newsletter builder. So we just
saw the newsletter writer skill. Now
we're going to run the newsletter
builder and I'm going to stay within the
same conversation with Cloud Code here
and I'm going to run  newsletter.
All right, so I'm going to run my
newsletter builder skill now and this
one is going to take the written content
and it's going to assemble the HTML
email. And then it's going to send it up
to Kit using the Kit API. All right, so
it's going to first confirm some of the
essential details like the issue number,
the subject line, the header, the main
message, the send time. So we're going
to say we're going to want to send it
tomorrow, April 2nd. And then sometimes
I include a call to action at the top.
This time I won't be doing that and I'll
just say that's all good. And yeah,
that's a good order. It's confirming.
Now the way that I have this newsletter
builder set up is that inside templates,
I have shell and this is like the outer
HTML shell of my email newsletter, but
then there's just this content tag which
is the bulk of the content of the email.
And then I have these individual HTML
templates that represent each individual
section. And these are pretty simple,
but sometimes they have a little bit of
styling and formatting built into them.
And sometimes they have like some
dynamic tags that I use in in Kit when
it gets into Kit. So it's going to use
the outer shell and then it's going to
insert each individual section that
we've already written into these
individual templates and ultimately
build a final HTML email. So let's see
how it's doing on that. Okay, so it has
generated the actual HTML email for this
entire message. Again, it uses that
outer shell with some CSS built into the
top. That's how you would normally do an
HTML email. And then it assembles the
rest of the actual content in nice clean
HTML according to exactly how I want my
design template to be. I don't have to
do this every single time. You know, the
skill and the agent just puts these
pieces together because it's all mapped
out in the process. And already it has
actually pushed it up to Kit and just to
show you real quick, I have this scripts
folder where we are, you know, running
this Python script which interacts with
the Kit V4 API and that is what enables
us to push it up into my Kit account.
And so now if I go into my Kit account,
there it is, marketing skills. So, you
know, here is that next builder
briefing. It's got the subject line, the
preview text, all of the content, it's
all in place exactly where I always want
it. All the details are dialed in. I've
got my call to action at the bottom for
those who are not pro members yet and I
can, you know, preview it and see how it
looks. And if I keep going through the
process, I can see that it's actually
scheduled for the time that I want it to
to send out. So there you go, those are
four of the agent skills, actually five,
that I built around repeatable processes
that I was already doing by hand. From
my agent's radar scan to keep tabs on
what's happening in my industry to
designing brand visuals to repurposing
videos to writing and sending my weekly
newsletter. Now here's the takeaway that
goes beyond marketing. The real skill,
the human skill here is observation.
Paying attention to the work that you
repeat every week, those patterns that
you follow without thinking about it.
Once you see them, you can document them
and then structure them into a skill
that you can delegate to an agent. And
this applies to every role, not just
marketing, not just development.
Wherever there's a recurring process,
there's a skill waiting to be built. Now
if you're wondering how I actually set
up my agents to run these skills using
OpenClaw, the multi-agent team, my
custom-built dashboard, the whole
system, I go deep on all of that in my
video on building a multi-agent team on
OpenClaw. So first, subscribe to the
channel so you don't miss my next video
on building with agents. And then I'll
see you over there next. Let's keep
building.